[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not an operating system?",
    "optionA": "Windows",
    "optionB": "Linux",
    "optionC": "Oracle",
    "optionD": "DOS",
    "answer": "Oracle"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first operating system developed?",
    "optionA": "1948",
    "optionB": "1949",
    "optionC": "1950",
    "optionD": "1951",
    "answer": "1950"
  },
  {
    "question": " Which of the following is the extension of Notepad?",
    "optionA": ".txt",
    "optionB": ".xls",
    "optionC": ".ppt",
    "optionD": ".bmp",
    "answer": ".txt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What else is a command interpreter called?",
    "optionA": "prompt",
    "optionB": "kernel",
    "optionC": "shell",
    "optionD": "command",
    "answer": "shell"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the full name of FAT?",
    "optionA": "File attribute table",
    "optionB": "File allocation table",
    "optionC": "Font attribute table",
    "optionD": "Format allocation table",
    "answer": "File allocation table"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the mean of the Booting in the operating system?",
    "optionA": "Restarting computer",
    "optionB": "Install the program",
    "optionC": "To scan",
    "optionD": "To turn off",
    "answer": "Restarting computer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Banker's algorithm is used?",
    "optionA": "To prevent deadlock",
    "optionB": "To deadlock recovery",
    "optionC": "To solve the deadlock",
    "optionD": "None of these",
    "answer": "To prevent deadlock"
  },
  {
    "question": "When you delete a file in your computer, where does it go?",
    "optionA": "Recycle bin",
    "optionB": "Hard disk",
    "optionC": "Taskbar",
    "optionD": "None of these",
    "answer": "Recycle bin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the Linux operating system?",
    "optionA": "Private operating system",
    "optionB": "Windows operating system",
    "optionC": "Open-source operating system",
    "optionD": "None of these",
    "answer": "Open-source operating system"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the full name of the DSM?",
    "optionA": "Direct system module",
    "optionB": "Direct system memory",
    "optionC": "Demoralized system memory",
    "optionD": "Distributed shared memory",
    "answer": "Distributed shared memory"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the full name of the IDL?",
    "optionA": "Interface definition language",
    "optionB": "Interface direct language",
    "optionC": "Interface data library",
    "optionD": "None of these",
    "answer": "Interface definition language"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is bootstrapping called?",
    "optionA": "Cold hot boot",
    "optionB": "Cold boot",
    "optionC": "Cold hot strap",
    "optionD": "Hot boot",
    "answer": "Cold boot"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the fence register used for?",
    "optionA": "To disk protection",
    "optionB": "To CPU protection",
    "optionC": "To memory protection",
    "optionD": "None of these",
    "answer": "To memory protection"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a single-user operating system?",
    "optionA": "Windows",
    "optionB": "MAC",
    "optionC": "Ms-Dos",
    "optionD": "None of these",
    "answer": "Ms-Dos"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not application software?",
    "optionA": "Windows 7",
    "optionB": "WordPad",
    "optionC": "Photoshop",
    "optionD": "MS-excel",
    "answer": "Windows 7"
  }
]
